<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Codifice</title>
    <link>https://codifice.uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Codifice</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://codifice.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Configuring a New EPiServer 6 R2 Website for Continuous Integration</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2012-11-22-notes-on-configuring-new-episerver-6-r2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2012-11-22-notes-on-configuring-new-episerver-6-r2/</guid>
      <description>I’m assuming that you’ve read the installation instructions:
http://world.episerver.com/Documentation/Items/Installation-Instructions/EPiServer-CMS/Version-6/EPiServer-CMS-6-R2/Installation-Instructions---EPiServer-CMS-6-R2/Creating a new blank EPiServer Site Project and Solution
Prepare Repository Check out trunk/main branch to working copy Create an Empty VS Solution root of the working copy Download the&amp;nbsp; 6R2 installer from EPiServer World (you’ll need to register): http://world.episerver.com/Download/Categories/Products/EPiServer-CMS/Run installer and deploy a Core deployment to the Working Copy, creating a project folder Open VS solution Add New Empty Website Project (use a temporary name) Configure project properties as required: Assembly Name (&amp;lt;client&amp;gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing MVC3 Validation Groups</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2012-01-15-announcing-mvc3-validation-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2012-01-15-announcing-mvc3-validation-groups/</guid>
      <description>I’ve recently had to organise the validation for long/multipart forms.&amp;nbsp; Ordinarily, you’d divide the form up into smaller models and create a wizard style user journey.&amp;nbsp; But in this case the UI design called for the user to arbitrarily jump back and forth between pages in the wizard and other restrictions meant that we couldn’t persist each sub-page on change.&amp;nbsp; What we needed were validation groups!
As this work involved a bit of the old copy-paste-adapt from the standard MVC code, it’s a bit complicated to go into the fine details of how to replicate the functionality for yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ektron: Finding “Missing” Content in the Index on 64bit Windows</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2011-11-01-ektron-finding-missing-content-in-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2011-11-01-ektron-finding-missing-content-in-index/</guid>
      <description>When content is created on an Ektron with a large content id (commonly on eSync enabled workareas) it may corrupt the content id.&amp;nbsp; For example if a new content item has an id of 6442451035 it will actually be indexed with a contentid of 2147483739.&amp;nbsp; This is because the original id is larger than an unsigned integer can hold. 1: long contentId = 6442451035;  2: Console.WriteLine((uint)contentId); //2147483739</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persisting the Page Title across Update Panel Post backs</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2011-08-16-persisting-page-title-across-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2011-08-16-persisting-page-title-across-update/</guid>
      <description>There’s a fun bug with AsyncPostbacks blanking out the Page Title (http://stackoverflow.com/questions/627378/page-losing-title-after-updatepanel-asyncpostback), the recommended fix is to rebind the page title on each Async Postback or to use the declarative page title attribute in the aspx.&amp;nbsp; My fix is to fix a JS bug in JS:
$(function(){ var prm = Sys.WebForms.PageRequestManager.getInstance(); if (!(prm)) return; document.orginalTitle=document.title; instance.add_endRequest(function(s, e){ if (document.title.replace(/\s/g,&amp;#34;&amp;#34;).length==0) document.title=document.orginalTitle; }); });  This JS code will ensure that the page title is persisted across ajax requests, with no changes to the server side code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ektron: Treating Office Files as Normal DMS Assets</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2011-08-04-ektron-treating-office-files-as-normal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2011-08-04-ektron-treating-office-files-as-normal/</guid>
      <description>One of the features of Ektron is tight office integration allowing the editing of office files directly from the workarea.&amp;nbsp; However, in some circumstances you may want to treat these as normal DMS assets (like PDF files) as their the end results of an offline publishing process.
The Ektron support fix for this is to modify the workarea files (detailed below), which would then need to be re-applyed with every upgrade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiments with ADO.Net, Extension Methods and Anonymous Methods</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2011-07-14-experiments-with-adonet-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2011-07-14-experiments-with-adonet-extension/</guid>
      <description>As much as at pains me to admit it, an ORM Framework is not the answer to all data access problems.&amp;nbsp; Sometimes the quickest, easiest and most maintainable approach is back-to-basics flat ADO.Net.&amp;nbsp; For those developers whose (development) life began with Entity Framework, NHibernate or SubSonic.&amp;nbsp; This is a fairly typical example of an ADO.Net method (in a well structured code base):
1: private static IEnumerable&amp;lt;ContentAwaitingApproval&amp;gt; GetPendingApprovals(long approvalGroupId)  2: {  3: List&amp;lt;ContentAwaitingApproval&amp;gt; approvals = new List&amp;lt;ContentAwaitingApproval&amp;gt;();  4: using (SqlConnection conn = new SqlConnection(ConfigurationManager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventing spamming from a mail forwarding address</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2011-07-08-preventing-spamming-from-mail/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2011-07-08-preventing-spamming-from-mail/</guid>
      <description>My webhosting company (arvixe) recently suspended my account due to a flood of ‘Inbox Full’ emails being sent to a mail forwarding alias (which then forwarded to the same accounts, which were full – D’Oh!).&amp;nbsp; After a bit of investigation it turns out some kind soul has been spoofing emails from that account.
Apparently, there’s a nice little DNS entry that you can add so that email servers can validate that the emails have only been sent from recognised servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from TFS 2008 to SVN 1.6 with tfs2svn</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2011-05-10-migrating-from-tfs-2008-to-svn-16-with/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2011-05-10-migrating-from-tfs-2008-to-svn-16-with/</guid>
      <description>This is tricky because tfs2svn stopped being updated when subversion 1.4 ruled the roost.&amp;nbsp; Here are the steps that I took:
 Have a subversion repository ready to receive the project (including ‘pre-revprop-change’ hook – mine is a simple ‘exit 0’ batch file) Install TortoiseSVN 1.6 Download Collabnets command line client for svn 1.6 (svn-win32-1.6.15.zip) Install tfs2svn 1.1 (http://sourceforge.net/projects/tfs2svn/files/tfs2svn/1.1/tfs2svn.setup.msi/download) on my development VM Extract the svn-win32 command line client and copy the contents of ‘bin’ folder over the contents in ‘C:\Program Files (x86)\Kevin Colyar\tfs2svn\libs\svn-win32-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging is the new Exception Swallowing</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2011-05-03-logging-is-new-exception-swallowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2011-05-03-logging-is-new-exception-swallowing/</guid>
      <description>For a long time now I’ve been stamping down hard on empty catch blocks in code, for obvious reasons.&amp;nbsp; When I can dictate coding standards that’s pretty much top the list.&amp;nbsp;   Every ‘catch’ block must (at a minimum) log or throw   I now realise I made a mistake with this rule...it should be:
  Every ‘catch’ block must (at a minimum) throw or log   It’s a subtle (the wording – not the formatting) difference in the way we need to think about this rule but it’s one I think we don’t think about enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Base26 Number Encoding/Generate Excel Columns</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2011-05-02-base26-number-encodinggenerate-excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2011-05-02-base26-number-encodinggenerate-excel/</guid>
      <description>Ever needed to convert an Excel Column Letter to a number or vice versa?&amp;nbsp; Here’s a couple of extension methods to do it:
1: public static string ToLetterEncoded(this Int32 numberToEncode)  2: {  3: if (numberToEncode &amp;lt;= 0) throw new ArgumentOutOfRangeException(&#34;numberToEncode&#34;, numberToEncode, &#34;Value must be greater than zero&#34;);  4: numberToEncode--;  5: if (numberToEncode &amp;gt;= 0 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; numberToEncode &amp;lt; 26)  6: return ((char)(&#39;A&#39; + numberToEncode)).ToString();  7: else  8: return ToLetterEncoded(numberToEncode / 26) + ToLetterEncoded(numberToEncode % 26 + 1);  9: }   1: public static Int32 FromLetterEncodedInt32(this string letterEncodedNumber)  2: {  3: if (letterEncodedNumber.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ektron: High Indexing Service Processor Usage (Potential) Fix</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-12-16-ektron-high-indexing-service-processor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-12-16-ektron-high-indexing-service-processor/</guid>
      <description>One of our larger client Ektron sites has had a history of poor performance that always seemed to be related to Indexing immediately after publishing content or syncing content to the live environment.&amp;nbsp; The site heavily uses indexed smart form fields and indexed metadata fields for ordering/sorting lists of content.
The symptoms were:
 High CIDAEMON processor usage (95-100% of a processor core)  Total Documents to Index in Indexing Service Manager getting stuck  Indexing Service ‘Service Too Busy’ exceptions  Analysing Crash Dumps of the CIDAEMON process shows the ‘hot’ thread stuck in the QLXFilter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EKTRON: Diagnosing 8.0 Extension Strategy Loading Failures</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-11-18-ektron-diagnosing-80-extension-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-11-18-ektron-diagnosing-80-extension-strategy/</guid>
      <description>I’ve recently hit a problem with deploying&amp;nbsp; Ektron Extensions (the 8.0 replacement for Plugins), essentially every time my Extension ‘Strategy’ was called the workarea would display an error similar to:
 Value cannot be null. Parameter name: type 
 Fortunately, in the Application Event log (for the CMS400 Source) there’s a bit more information:
1: Timestamp: 18/11/2010 18:43:01  2: Message: Could not load the MartinOnDotNet.Helpers.Ektron.Extensions.Monitoring.UserMonitoringStrategy, MartinOnDotNet.Helpers.Ektron.Extensions.Monitoring implementation from the configuration file  3: Category: Error  4: Priority: -1  5: EventId: 0  6: Severity: Error   This shows that the declaration in the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance: Applying Output Cache Policies to a User Controls</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-11-03-performance-applying-output-cache/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-11-03-performance-applying-output-cache/</guid>
      <description>One of the great features in ASP.NET is the rich caching framework.&amp;nbsp; I particularly like being able to:
 Define caching policies in the configuration file and then assigning those policies to groups of pages (via the @@OutputCache directive).  Cache User Control output for reuse on multiple pages (Partial Page Caching)   What I don’t like is the fact that you can’t combine the two!&amp;nbsp; You have to hard code your user control cache directives either in the mark-up (as @@OutputCache directive) or by applying an attribute (System.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL: Cleaning Up After the Database Tuning Engine Advisor</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-11-01-sql-cleaning-up-after-database-tuning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-11-01-sql-cleaning-up-after-database-tuning/</guid>
      <description>I’ve recently had to do a quick bit of DB performance analysis work on a 3rd Party database to see if I can improve performance(without being too invasive).&amp;nbsp; The quickest way to do this, is using the Database Tuning Engine Advisor tool that comes with SQL 2008 (the best way is to have loads of experience and a tonne of time to properly analyse the database). Part of my analysis procedure was to make a script of queries that I could run with and without the DTA recommended indexes to evaluate any real world improvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure: Replacing a Dead RAID 5 Drive in QNAP NAS</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-10-30-infrastructure-replacing-dead-raid-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-10-30-infrastructure-replacing-dead-raid-5/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a while since I last posted – it’s been crazy busy at work – and this is a completely non-.Net related post (sorry).&amp;nbsp; However, like many of you (I’m&amp;nbsp; sure) I’ve got a personal SVN repository (where I keep my .Net code, so there is a tenuous link!) which is hosted on my QNAP 419P NAS Drive on a RAID5 volume across 4 Hot Swappable Disks.&amp;nbsp; For the non-technical, this is a little whizzy box with tonnes of space and can withstand a single complete hard disk failure without loosing data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security: Protect against POET Attacks with Custom Errors!</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-09-20-security-protect-against-poet-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-09-20-security-protect-against-poet-attacks/</guid>
      <description>There’s been a big deal made of a serious security flaw in ASP.Net which potentially affects a lot of .Net sites, that allows a 3rd Party to trick ASP.Net into serving sensitive files within a web application folder.&amp;nbsp; Microsoft have released official advise on how to temporarily patch the problem which revolves around forcing Error&amp;nbsp; and Page Not found pages to return the same status page.&amp;nbsp; This would need to stay in place until a permanent fix is released.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yummy! Cleaner, sweeter WCF proxy usage with DynamicTidyProxy!</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-09-05-yummy-cleaner-sweeter-wcf-proxy-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-09-05-yummy-cleaner-sweeter-wcf-proxy-usage/</guid>
      <description>This is a follow up to my previous (in fact my first) post “Mmmmm… clean, sweet WCF proxy usage with TidyProxy!”, which showed how to safely use an arbitrary WCF proxy class safely.&amp;nbsp; 
A substantial part of my day-to-day development is working with WCF services, mainly web and MSMQ and after a few teething troubles everything’s been ticking along nicely.&amp;nbsp; Generally these are internal windows-&amp;gt;web comm’s where I can control both client and server implementations, so lots of shared types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: Creating Strongly Typed Code Using Microsoft.VisualBasic.Collection</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-08-18-howto-creating-strongly-typed-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-08-18-howto-creating-strongly-typed-code/</guid>
      <description>One of the 3rd Party CMS’s that I frequently work with (Ektron) has a lot of legacy API code that uses Microsoft.VisualBasic.Collections ( from hereon referred to as Collection) to pass data into the database.&amp;nbsp; These API’s methods are slowly being replaced with strongly typed entity style methods, but the most stable and reliable methods use Collections.
There are many reasons to dislike Collections, but my top ones are:
 You can’t see the key’s of the values inside – this often leads to Exception led logic  Weakly Typed   What’s in the Box?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Better FindControl</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-08-03-building-better-findcontrol/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-08-03-building-better-findcontrol/</guid>
      <description>There are times in any semi-advanced ASP.NET developers life when they’re working with databound templated controls (such as the Repeater) and they need to find a control without knowing where it is, or even if its there.
Normally, you’re reduced to using the standard FindControl method available on any control.&amp;nbsp; But this only finds controls with a given id within the same NamingContainer.&amp;nbsp; I’ve written some extension methods to try and get around the (many) issues that I’ve had with FindControl and hopefully people will find them useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ektron: SQL Script To Clone A Menu into Multiple Languages</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-07-27-ektron-sql-script-to-clone-menu-into/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-07-27-ektron-sql-script-to-clone-menu-into/</guid>
      <description>I’ve recently needed to have a multilingual menu where the id for each menu item is the same across all languages, this is a bit of a tall order using the workarea as only the root menu item will share the id.
So I’ve knocked out a quick’n’dirty TSQL script to clone a menu across across several languages whilst maintaining the relevant ids.
1: BEGIN TRANSACTION  2:&amp;nbsp;   3: CREATE TABLE #NewMenu (  4: [mnu_id] [bigint] NOT NULL,  5: [mnu_name] [nvarchar](255) NULL,  6: [mnu_description] [nvarchar](255) NULL,  7: [folder_id] [bigint] NOT NULL,  8: [recursive] [int] NOT NULL,  9: [user_id] [bigint] NULL,  10: [date_created] [datetime] NOT NULL,  11: [last_edit_date] [datetime] NULL,  12: [last_edit_lname] [nvarchar](50) NOT NULL,  13: [last_edit_fname] [nvarchar](50) NOT NULL,  14: [mnu_type] [int] NOT NULL,  15: [mnu_link] [nvarchar](255) NULL,  16: [template_link] [nvarchar](255) NULL,  17: [parent_id] [bigint] NULL,  18: [ancestor_id] [bigint] NULL,  19: [content_language] [int] NOT NULL,  20: [mnu_image] [nvarchar](512) NULL,  21: [mnu_image_override] [int] NULL,  22: [mnu_to_folders] [nvarchar](512) NULL,  23: [mnu_to_templates] [nvarchar](255) NULL,  24: [dynamic_replication_method] [int] NULL)  25: GO  26:&amp;nbsp;   27: WITH MenuCTE AS (  28: SELECT *  29: FROM [dbo].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ektron: Safely Impersonating Users within Ektron</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-07-21-ektron-safely-impersonating-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-07-21-ektron-safely-impersonating-users/</guid>
      <description>I recently hit an scenario where I needed to impersonate a lesser privileged workarea user to perform some content creation/approvals whilst working within the Approval Chain. My initial attempts leveraged my ElevatedPermissionScope class, which failed with an error similar to:
1: System.Exception: Index was outside the bounds of the   2: array.[EkSite--&amp;gt;;GetPermissions(Int,Int,Int,String,[&amp;amp;Collection)]][EkSite-&amp;gt;GetPermissions(Int,Int,String,[&amp;amp;Collection]]  3: at   4: Ektron.Cms.EkException.ThrowException(Exception ex, EventLogEntryType EventType)  5: at   6: Ektron.Cms.EkException.ThrowException(Exception ex)  7: at   8: Ektron.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing A Master Page Body Tag’s CSS Class For Different Content Pages</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-07-20-changing-master-page-body-tags-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-07-20-changing-master-page-body-tags-css/</guid>
      <description>It seems a bit of a failing of Master Pages that there’s no clear way to assign different CSS classes to the ‘body’ tag based on the Content Page.&amp;nbsp; To get around this, I’ve taken to inheriting all of my content pages from a known base class (which in turn inherits from System.Web.Page) and then giving it a publically accessible property of ‘BodyCssClass’!
1: namespace MartinOnDotNet.MasterPageBodyClass  2: {  3: public class BasePage : System.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIP: How to Handle Form Postbacks when Url Rewriting</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-07-15-tip-how-to-handle-form-postbacks-when/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-07-15-tip-how-to-handle-form-postbacks-when/</guid>
      <description>Url Rewriting is great and I love it a lot, you get to create nice readable (and memorable) urls without having to create hundred of files.&amp;nbsp; However, there can be issues.&amp;nbsp; For example, when you post back to a page where the url has been rewritten, it won’t be to the nice alias, it will be to the direct page.aspx?id=blah location.&amp;nbsp; Which is a bit nasty.
To stop this, I make use of a Control Adapters which alters the rendering logic of the HtmlForm control on every ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diagnosing Tricky ASP.Net Production Issues with DebugDiag and winDbg</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-07-10-diagnosing-tricky-aspnet-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-07-10-diagnosing-tricky-aspnet-production/</guid>
      <description>Issues that (appear to) occur only in production can be very frustrating.&amp;nbsp; Recently, I’ve had difficulty with a ‘normal’ product upgrade introducing several features and fixes… the code base worked in development, passed QA and passed UAT in the staging environment.&amp;nbsp; However, 5 minutes after deploying to live the w3wp process crashes, shortly followed by the other servers in the cluster.
Bugger.
A quick look in the event logs show no unusual errors logged by the application, but the Application log records this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIP: Improve Readability with Shorter String.Format Statements</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-07-01-tip-improve-readability-with-shorter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-07-01-tip-improve-readability-with-shorter/</guid>
      <description>String.Format is a wonderful method, a real life saver when it comes to producing (readable) formatted text from within code.&amp;nbsp; I use it everywhere, but it gets a bit tedious typing the same boilerplate code to use it properly:
1: string formatted = string.Format(CultureInfo.InvariantCulture, &#34;Formatted text {0:-15} example generated on {1:d}&#34;, meaningfulString, DateTime.Now);   

That “string.Format(CultureInfo.InvariantCulture,” over 40 characters before you get the meat of the statement.&amp;nbsp; Sure you can drop the invariant culture bit but then you can introduce weird formatting problems on different machines….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert Accented Characters to Simple Characters</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-28-convert-accented-characters-to-simple/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-28-convert-accented-characters-to-simple/</guid>
      <description>I recently needed a way to replace accented characters with simple english ones to allow more readable friendly urls. I&#39;m sure there are plenty of Danes out there who are sick of seeing their language butchered by UrlEncode.&amp;nbsp; After bit of reading up, it seems .Net 2.0 does 99% of the heavy lifting for you:
1: //using System.Text;  2:&amp;nbsp;   3: /// &amp;lt;summary&amp;gt;  4: /// Replaces Accented Characters with Closest Equivalents  5: /// &amp;lt;/summary&amp;gt;  6: /// &amp;lt;param name=&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSBuild: Reliably Retrieving the Assembly Version (without locking the file!)</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-24-msbuild-reliably-retrieving-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-24-msbuild-reliably-retrieving-assembly/</guid>
      <description>I’ve recently had to look at dynamically assigning an assembly versions based in part on the date of compilation and the version of a compiled 3rd Party library.
This looked like a simple job for the MSBuild.ExtensionPack.Framework.Assembly task in the MSBuild Extension Pack.&amp;nbsp; However, this had a serious downside it locked the Assembly for the duration of the build!.&amp;nbsp; Erkk.
This is the Devil Line that causes the problem:
1: protected override void InternalExecute()  2: {  3: // Implementation ommitted  4: this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIP: How to Debug Windows Services and Plugins</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-23-tip-how-to-debug-windows-services-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-23-tip-how-to-debug-windows-services-and/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve ever had to create an component hosted inside a 3rd Party application (such as a plugin or windows service), you’ll know that it can be pretty tricky to get the debugger attached to the process quickly and reliably.&amp;nbsp; Here’s a snippet that’s I’ve taken from project to project:
1: #if DEBUG  2: if (Properties.Settings.Default.LaunchDebugger  3: &amp;amp;&amp;amp; !System.Diagnostics.Debugger.IsAttached) System.Diagnostics.Debugger.Launch();  4: #endif   
This is statement checks to see if launching the debugger is allowed (using the standard settings classes) and launches the debugger if one isn’t already attached.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ektron: Fix for Primary Key Constraint Error When Creating A User</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-22-ektron-fix-for-primary-key-constraint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-22-ektron-fix-for-primary-key-constraint/</guid>
      <description>We’ve recently had an issue with creating users in our Ektron 8.0.1 installation where we could no longer create users.&amp;nbsp; The error we got was:
 Error cms_addUser: Error[cms_SetupDefaultNotificationPreferencesForUser]:
Violation of PRIMARY KEY constraint &#39;PK_notification_preference_default&#39;.
Cannot insert duplicate key in object &#39;dbo.notification_preference_default&#39;.
[EkUser-&amp;gt;AddUserv2_0][UserApi-&amp;gt;AddUser]  Scary Stuff.
Still, the Ektron provided fixes are simple enough (although by no means intuitive!):
Simple Fix  Restart Ektron Windows Services  Perform a full eSync (from Synchronisation screen)   Complex Fix If the above doesn’t work try this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tip: Constructing Private Types</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-16-tip-constructing-private-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-16-tip-constructing-private-types/</guid>
      <description>I recently needed to create an instance of the System.Web.StaticFileHandler.&amp;nbsp; This is a bit difficult as the class is internal so reflection must be used:
1: private static IHttpHandler _staticFileHandler;  2:&amp;nbsp;   3: private static IHttpHandler StaticFileHandler  4: {  5: get  6: {  7: if (_staticFileHandler == null)  8: {  9: Assembly systemWeb = typeof(IHttpHandler).Assembly;  10: /* If you don&#39;t have a public type to reference a lookup like this could be done  11: Assembly systemWeb = AppDomain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VWT2OC: The Host Is Dead! Long Live the Host!</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-16-vwt2oc-host-is-dead-long-live-host/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-16-vwt2oc-host-is-dead-long-live-host/</guid>
      <description>My WebHost4Life Trials are over.&amp;nbsp; I was finally let in to a secret cabal of WH4L users who know the secret truth behind the ‘migration’ myth….the old control panel still exists!&amp;nbsp; Yay!&amp;nbsp; It only took a week of chasing support staff daily.&amp;nbsp; So, now I’ve got control of the database, DNS records, etc, etc.&amp;nbsp; VWT2OC has moved to it’s new home with Arvixe.&amp;nbsp; The page load for the n2cms build has dropped from ~15s to ~4s from an empty cache and the first request time for a freshly recycled app pool is ~10 seconds – not a minute!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ektron 8.01: PlatformNotSupportedException – Tracking Down and Fixing Another Multilingual Gotcha!</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-15-ektron-801-platformnotsupportedexceptio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-15-ektron-801-platformnotsupportedexceptio/</guid>
      <description>I’m still tracing though issues after upgrading to 8.01, this time looking at why requests for static files are return 500 - Internal Server Errors when French is selected, but not English. Hmm.
Looking at the Event Logs shows lots of errors like this:
1: Exception type: PlatformNotSupportedException   2:&amp;nbsp;   3: Exception message: The DefaultHttpHandler.BeginProcessRequest method is not   4: supported by IIS integrated pipeline mode.    This is telling me that I’m trying to serve a file via the IIS 7 Integrated Pipeline using a handler that’s specifically designed for IIS 6 (or IIS Classic Pipeline).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ektron 8.0.1: Fixing New Handlers Multilingual Bug</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-14-ektron-801-fixing-new-handlers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-14-ektron-801-fixing-new-handlers/</guid>
      <description>I recently had to upgrade an multilingual Ektron project and all went relatively well.&amp;nbsp; However, whilst debugging the site – I noticed that we were getting a lot of Formatting Exceptions when running the site in French (fr-FR) but not English (en-GB).&amp;nbsp; I tracked this down to the new ‘workarea/csslib/ektronCss.ashx’ and ‘workarea/java/ektronJs.ashx’ handlers and in particular around the mechanism for parsing the ‘If-Modified-Since’ header:
1: public class ektronCss : IHttpHandler {  2:   3: public void ProcessRequest (HttpContext context)   4: {  5: // Ommitted for clarity until line 19   6: CultureInfo provider = CultureInfo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N2CMS Meet VWT2OC: Day 7 – Soldiering On</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-12-n2cms-meet-vwt2oc-day-7-soldiering-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-12-n2cms-meet-vwt2oc-day-7-soldiering-on/</guid>
      <description>Well, WebHost4Life are still trying to fix their migration issues (72 hours and counting!) which have taken down the current website and database which has quite effectively stopped my actual development on the project.&amp;nbsp; D’oh!&amp;nbsp; Apparently, the failure is so severe that they can’t even provide a back up of the database.&amp;nbsp; Double D’oh!&amp;nbsp; This has pretty much derailed my project plan….
I’ll definitely be recommending we jump ship and go with a better hosting provider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogger Tweak:  Making Code Snippets More Usable</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-10-blogger-tweak-making-code-snippets-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-10-blogger-tweak-making-code-snippets-more/</guid>
      <description>Now that I’m blogging more code snippet heavy content it’s becoming apparent that the excellent Code Snippet Plugin with Windows Live Writer isn’t the most usable for people trying to copy the snippet for their own use.&amp;nbsp; So I’ve created a Blogger Template tweak to automatically add a ‘plain text/formatted’ toggle.&amp;nbsp; To install simply copy the snippet below into your Blogger Template just above the &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt; tag.
1: &amp;lt;script type=&#39;text/javascript&#39;&amp;gt;  2: var ChildText = function(nodeList) {  3: var text = &amp;amp;#39;&amp;amp;#39;;  4: for (var j = nodeList.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N2CMS Templates RSS Feed Fix</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-10-n2cms-templates-rss-feed-fix/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-10-n2cms-templates-rss-feed-fix/</guid>
      <description>N2CMS comes with some pretty fully featured examples, the most useful to me is the N2.Templates example site.&amp;nbsp; Unfortunately, as it stands the RSS feed is broken and give the error:
Cannot use filters when using MaxResults, sorry. Fortunately a fix can be found the N2.Templates.Mvc project, you just need to replace the following functions in N2.Templates.Items.RssFeed :
1: public virtual IEnumerable&amp;lt;ISyndicatable&amp;gt; GetItems()  2: {  3: foreach (ISyndicatable item in N2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N2CMS Forum Addon: Fixing the Theme</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-09-n2cms-forum-addon-fixing-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-09-n2cms-forum-addon-fixing-theme/</guid>
      <description>My work on the VWT2OC site is on hiatus at the moment due to hosting issues so I thought I’d blog a useful fix that I’ve found.
I’ve noticed a bug with the Forum Addon.&amp;nbsp; The first page would be correctly themed but any subsequent pages were not when running against a build of the latest N2CMS.
On investigation it seems that the Forum Pages CurrentItem was resolving to null which prevented the ThemeConcern for assigning the correct theme:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N2CMS Meet VWT2OC: Day 4 – Wheel Spinning</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-09-n2cms-meet-vwt2oc-day-4-wheel-spinning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-09-n2cms-meet-vwt2oc-day-4-wheel-spinning/</guid>
      <description>Well, Webhost4Life have yet to restore the current site so I can’t work through the develop model/import data/rinse/repeat iterations which I’ll need to ensure a clean migration at the end of the project.&amp;nbsp; Still at least they’re keeping me updated…and not at all keeping me in the dark with vague promised that someone&#39;s working on it.&amp;nbsp; Bastards.
I guess it’s my fault for trusting them to do all the database backups (like they’re paid to do)….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N2CMS Meet VWT2OC: Day 3 – Grinding to a Halt!</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-08-n2cms-meet-vwt2oc-day-3-grinding-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-08-n2cms-meet-vwt2oc-day-3-grinding-to/</guid>
      <description>Well, it was going way too well to last.&amp;nbsp; It’s become apparent that the existing site is in some sort of half migrated mangled state after the hosting provider changed systems.&amp;nbsp; This has been like a half-brick to the head as when they’ve tried to fix the issue, more and more keep getting uncovered.&amp;nbsp; The sites been down for most of the day as a result (and is still down 24 hours later ….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N2CMS Meet VWT2OC: Day 2 – N2CMS Configuration</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-07-n2cms-meet-vwt2oc-day-2-n2cms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-07-n2cms-meet-vwt2oc-day-2-n2cms/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday went well and I’ve now got the basic N2CMS install working and the Forum Addon has been installed, so my objectives for today are:
 Day 2 – N2CMS Configuration  Integrate the Membership Provider from n2cms/forum/legacy vwt2oc  Construct basic site structure (homepage/articles/forum/gallery/events calendar/etc)  Create VWT2OC basic theme     Integrating the Membership Provider One of the first tasks I need to undertake is integrating the underlying security model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N2CMS Meet VWT2OC: Day 1 – Project Setup</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-06-n2cms-meet-vwt2oc-day-1-project-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-06-06-n2cms-meet-vwt2oc-day-1-project-setup/</guid>
      <description>It’s on!&amp;nbsp; I’ve got 8 days to overhaul the Volkswagen Type 2 Owners Club (www.vwt2oc.com) before work beckons again….&amp;nbsp; A month ago I decided to rebuild the existing website using n2cms.&amp;nbsp; Unfortunately, in that time when I was going to research best practise and get some test sites working….I’ve done nothing.&amp;nbsp; So, I’ve decided to incentivise myself by blogging my progress….
My Basic Plan of Action is:
 Day 1 – Project Setup  SVN Configuration  Create Build Script to compile N2CMS for project  Integrate Forum Add On with n2cms    Day 2 – N2CMS Configuration  Integrate the Membership Provider from n2cms/forum/legacy vwt2oc  Construct basic site structure (homepage/articles/forum/gallery/events calendar/etc)  Create VWT2OC basic theme    Day 3 – VWT2OC Membership Model  Implement Club Member/Membership Data Model in n2cms  Basic Admin Screens for Members  Initial member import routine from current site    Day 4 – My Account and Personalization  Improve member import routine  Membership Reports/Maintenance from with N2CMS  Initial ‘My Account’ page for front end    Day 5 – End User Approval/eCommerce  Deploy to temporary hosted location for client approval of WIP  Import Membership Purchasing Mechanism for legacy app  Integrate NoChex/Paypal payment gateways    Day 6 – Review of Progress  Review functionality and prioritise urgent issues with work so far    Day 7 + 8 – Getting a functional site   Ha!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Control of Your Control Adapters</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-05-23-taking-control-of-your-control-adapters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-05-23-taking-control-of-your-control-adapters/</guid>
      <description>I was recently put in a difficult position when I was attempting to integrate some of our reliable, established Control Adapters into a new Ektron project.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; When the Ektron workarea controls were ‘adapted’ (in this case a checkbox) it broke some supporting JQuery statements.&amp;nbsp; So the quandary I found my self in was, so I amend the workarea code to add the control attribute to ‘opt-out’ of using the adapter, or modify the control adapters (and all of their dependent projects) to use an ‘opt-in’ attribute instead?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Example of On-The-Fly Config Section Encryption</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-05-13-basic-example-of-on-fly-config-section/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-05-13-basic-example-of-on-fly-config-section/</guid>
      <description>I recently answered a question about how you could securely modify a value within an encrypted configuration website without having to create a duplicate config file.&amp;nbsp; Well, the answer’s pretty simple and straightforward – just use the API!
A quick example page could be:
1: &amp;lt;%@@ Page Language=&#34;C#&#34; AutoEventWireup=&#34;true&#34; CodeFile=&#34;Default.aspx.cs&#34; Inherits=&#34;_Default&#34; %&amp;gt;  2:&amp;nbsp;   3: &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC &#34;-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Transitional//EN&#34; &#34;http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-transitional.dtd&#34;&amp;gt;  4: &amp;lt;html xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&#34;&amp;gt;  5: &amp;lt;head runat=&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N2CMS Meet VWT2OC: Project History</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-05-10-n2cms-meet-vwt2oc-project-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-05-10-n2cms-meet-vwt2oc-project-history/</guid>
      <description>Many moons ago (~3 years) I did a bit of family rate development to create a simple website for the Volkswagen Type 2 Owners Club – www.vwt2oc.com.&amp;nbsp; The brief was fairly sparse on detail, they needed a website to manage their memberships and take orders online, a few content manages pages and a basic forum to take over from their previous mainly static site that was looking a little long in the tooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using MbUnit StaticTestFactory to Validate Sitemap.xml Links</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-05-05-using-mbunit-statictestfactory-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-05-05-using-mbunit-statictestfactory-to/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been investigating a replacement for our current link checker (SEO Optimization Toolkit) to be run automatically as part of our build so that we can get a quick heads up if one of our dynamic pages breaks.&amp;nbsp; The problem is that as most of our sites are built with Ektron there’s a lot of potential for a combination of content and code to break individual pages that share a template with working pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing the Precompilation Marker File Ektron Issue on IIS 7</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-22-fixing-precompilation-marker-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-22-fixing-precompilation-marker-file/</guid>
      <description>After recently updating a 7.65 based website to 8.0 we recently found that parts of the workarea were unusable.&amp;nbsp; The upgrade went well and all the pre-deployment checks went well.&amp;nbsp; However, when we performed the UAT deployment the workarea was broken.&amp;nbsp; Where the treeview menu on the left should be, there was a helpful message:
 This is a marker file generated by the precompilation tool, and should not be deleted!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevating Ektron User Permissions Safely</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-19-elevating-ektron-user-permissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-19-elevating-ektron-user-permissions/</guid>
      <description>When you’re coding against the Ektron API you frequently find yourself needing to add/modify content as a result of a user action or similar privileged tasks.&amp;nbsp; To do this you need to impersonate a more privileged user (such as&amp;nbsp; InternalAdmin) for the duration of the task and then revert to the current users privileges. The approach most frequently quoted on the Ektron dev forums is along the lines of:
1: public void DoElevatedPermission()  2: {  3: int currentCallerId;  4: int currentUserId;  5:&amp;nbsp;   6: Ektron.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Concurrent Logins in Ektron</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-16-enabling-concurrent-logins-in-ektron/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-16-enabling-concurrent-logins-in-ektron/</guid>
      <description>For one of our major clients we needed a semi-secure area – you needed credentials to view the content within, but there was only one set of credentials.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This meant that multiple users could access the site concurrently with the same credentials and this is a bit of a problem for the Ektron security model as it’s based around a one session per login model.
This model is enforced by a unique integer that is generated on login and persisted in the database (in [dbo].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IIS 7 Gotcha! 404.13 Not Found – Uploading Large Files with Integrated Pipeline!</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-13-iis-7-gotcha-40413-not-found-uploading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-13-iis-7-gotcha-40413-not-found-uploading/</guid>
      <description>Whilst uploading a large (70MB) file to an IIS 7 website I got a 404 error….which was odd, uploading a file in a postback shouldn’t give me that.&amp;nbsp; I know that file exists!
On further investigation it turns out it was actually a 404.13 error from the Request Filtering feature of the Integrated Pipeline (more info: http://bit.ly/dkZiYr).&amp;nbsp; To fix this I needed to add some additional configuration to the &amp;lt;system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Windows 7 Development VM Load Out</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-10-my-windows-7-development-vm-load-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-10-my-windows-7-development-vm-load-out/</guid>
      <description>Well, it was bound to happen.&amp;nbsp; I rebuilt my PC and forgot to install my dev tools… oh well.&amp;nbsp; In an attempt to stop this from ever happening again, I’m creating a dev VM which will be backed up onto my NAS device.
The applications I’m installing for (ASP.Net Development) are:
 VMWare Player 3.0.1 (FileHippo)  2GB Memory  1 Processor  Bridged Network  40GB C: (System and Applications)  60GB D: (Data)    Windows 7 Professional x64  Firefox with Extensions:  Firebug  YSlow  Web Developer Toolbar  HTML Validator  Selenium IDE    Microsoft Web Platform Installer  Web Platform  Web Server – Recommended Products + SEO Toolkit  Framework – Recommended Products + ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ektron: A Fix For Uploading Assets into a Folder Called Assets</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-08-ektron-fix-for-uploading-assets-into/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-08-ektron-fix-for-uploading-assets-into/</guid>
      <description>An interesting bug came in today from a client that had been uploading content and images into their workarea for their upcoming release.&amp;nbsp; Most of their images weren’t being displayed on the site or in the workarea.
When the image url was navigated to directly, instead of an server error or file not found we saw this:
 Error: Asset requested doesn&#39;t exist in the system
 I beg to differ!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure Your Website, Put Bouncers at the Door (Part 3)</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-08-secure-your-website-put-bouncers-at_08/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-08-secure-your-website-put-bouncers-at_08/</guid>
      <description>In part 1, I gave an overview of the similarities in securing a good night club and a website and in part 2 I gave an overview of what we, as developers, can do to secure our websites.&amp;nbsp; In this final part, I give details on how we should be doing the most important (and mundane) part of securing our websites:
 1. Input Validation (Continued) One important fact that many web developers fail to take on board, is that everything you receive from the client is a string; Query strings, post back values and cookies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure Your Website, Put Bouncers at the Door (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-06-secure-your-website-put-bouncers-at_06/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-06-secure-your-website-put-bouncers-at_06/</guid>
      <description>In part 1, I gave an overview of the similarities in securing a good night club and a website.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; In this part I’ll give an overview of what we as developers can do to implement these measures:
 4 and 5 Authentication and HTTPS The implementation of these is very much driven by the business requirements of the site, if the site’s free to access and there’s no personal information they’re a non-issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Educating Clients About The Way the Web Works</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-05-educating-clients-about-way-web-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-05-educating-clients-about-way-web-works/</guid>
      <description>Craig’s pointed out an interesting discussion about managing client expectations (that kicked off from a very preachy design article) around the final display of a website across browsers.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This sort of discussion has been around for a while now and I think clients are starting to wise up to browser display issues.
Personally, I’m fairly indifferent about how most websites look provided they behave as I expect don’t actively get in my way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure Your Website, Put Bouncers at the Door (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-04-secure-your-website-put-bouncers-at/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-04-secure-your-website-put-bouncers-at/</guid>
      <description>A good website is much like a nightclub, we want the general population to be able to use the facilities freely (or for a nominal fee!) but we don’t want the trouble makers that will spoil it for everyone.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Pushing the analogy further, nightclubs have a few different types of security in place:
  Visibility Implementation Mitigates   High Profile Bouncers  Filter out trouble makers at point of entry    &amp;nbsp; Internal Security Eject people that become troublemakers   Low Profile Bars on Windows Alarmed Exits Prevent people sneaking in   &amp;nbsp; Metal Detectors Security Cameras Passively check for people about to cause trouble   As web developers we have a very similar set of tools that we can use to secure our website:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ektron and Web Application Projects (Part 3)</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-03-27-ektron-compiled-workarea-workaround/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-03-27-ektron-compiled-workarea-workaround/</guid>
      <description>In this series of posts I’ve described a method of keeping your code and the required Ektron workarea separated.&amp;nbsp; This method essentially turns the ‘drop-in compiled workarea’ feature request on it’s head, by dropping your compiled code into the work area.&amp;nbsp; It’s the same result, just a slightly difference process (that you can do right now!):
 In Part 1, I discussed why you might want to develop your website outside of the default Ektron workarea and gave a brief overview of your options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ektron and Web Application Projects (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-03-24-ektron-and-web-application-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-03-24-ektron-and-web-application-projects/</guid>
      <description>In Part 1, I discussed why you might want to develop your website outside of the default Ektron workarea and gave a brief overview of your options.
This time around, I’m going to show how to configure your Visual Studio Solution and projects and IIS to get you started.
You will need:
 A standard Ektron cms400min workarea website (I usually just call mine /Web – and copy directly from a fresh cms400min install!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diagnosing an Ektron eSync Relationship</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-03-23-ektron-esync-error-servicechannel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-03-23-ektron-esync-error-servicechannel/</guid>
      <description>Ektron’s eSync service is a great product when it’s working but getting the initial configuration right can be a bit fiddly.&amp;nbsp; I’ve compiled a quick diagnostic procedure to resolve the most common issues, as well as some of the more common issues.
Note: The Ektron Windows Service is usually in: C:\Program Files\Ektron\EktronWindowsService30. After any configuration change restart the Ektron Windows Service on every node in the relationship.
 Restart the Ektron Windows Service on every node within the relationship  Ensure that the Ektron license is valid for every database within the relationship  Ensure that you can access http://&amp;lt;DOMAINNAME&amp;gt;/workarea/ServerControlWS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ektron and Web Application Projects (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-03-22-working-with-ektron-using-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-03-22-working-with-ektron-using-web/</guid>
      <description>Like a lot of enterprise CMS production Ektron expects you to work in a particular way and provides lots of help for non-developers to quickly produce websites with minimal technical skills.&amp;nbsp; But what if you have more technical needs?
One of the downsides (in my opinion) of developing websites against Ektron, is the expectation that you will be integrating your code into the existing workarea Web Site Project.&amp;nbsp; Now, there are pros and cons on Web Site over Web Application projects but the big disadvantage for me is the sheer size of the workarea brings Visual Studio to a crawl when your editing code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.Net and Custom Error Pages, an SEO nightmare?</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-03-20-aspnet-and-custom-error-pages-seo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-03-20-aspnet-and-custom-error-pages-seo/</guid>
      <description>It’s a (conscientious) developer’s worst fear:
 You’ve slaved long and hard to produce a top-notch, blistering fast website that fully shows off your coding prowess and skills, you unveil the website to critical acclaim and universal client approval (imagine the cheering crowds) but then out-of-hours the database server fails!&amp;nbsp; Yerrk!
All the developer’s are out celebrating a successful so no-one notices the log file growing bigger and bigger, screaming to be heard….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mmmmm… clean, sweet WCF proxy usage with TidyProxy!</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-03-20-mmmmm-clean-sweet-wcf-proxy-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-03-20-mmmmm-clean-sweet-wcf-proxy-usage/</guid>
      <description>Everyone knows (hopefully) how WCF has made multi-tiered application development easier and cleaner.&amp;nbsp; You get nicely generated client proxies that reuse common libraries straight out of Visual Studio – no more having to convert between your DTOs and the Web Service DTOs.&amp;nbsp; They even implement IDisposable - you can just wrap them in using statements and you’re good to go!&amp;nbsp; How neat is that!
1: using (var proxy = new TidyProxy&amp;lt;SomeWCFServiceClient&amp;gt;()) 2: { 3: proxy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>