<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>web site project on Codifice</title>
    <link>https://codifice.uk/tags/web-site-project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in web site project on Codifice</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://codifice.uk/tags/web-site-project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Example of On-The-Fly Config Section Encryption</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-05-13-basic-example-of-on-fly-config-section/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-05-13-basic-example-of-on-fly-config-section/</guid>
      <description>I recently answered a question about how you could securely modify a value within an encrypted configuration website without having to create a duplicate config file.&amp;nbsp; Well, the answer’s pretty simple and straightforward – just use the API!
A quick example page could be:
1: &amp;lt;%@@ Page Language=&#34;C#&#34; AutoEventWireup=&#34;true&#34; CodeFile=&#34;Default.aspx.cs&#34; Inherits=&#34;_Default&#34; %&amp;gt;  2:&amp;nbsp;   3: &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC &#34;-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Transitional//EN&#34; &#34;http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-transitional.dtd&#34;&amp;gt;  4: &amp;lt;html xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&#34;&amp;gt;  5: &amp;lt;head runat=&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ektron and Web Application Projects (Part 3)</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-03-27-ektron-compiled-workarea-workaround/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-03-27-ektron-compiled-workarea-workaround/</guid>
      <description>In this series of posts I’ve described a method of keeping your code and the required Ektron workarea separated.&amp;nbsp; This method essentially turns the ‘drop-in compiled workarea’ feature request on it’s head, by dropping your compiled code into the work area.&amp;nbsp; It’s the same result, just a slightly difference process (that you can do right now!):
 In Part 1, I discussed why you might want to develop your website outside of the default Ektron workarea and gave a brief overview of your options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ektron and Web Application Projects (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-03-24-ektron-and-web-application-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-03-24-ektron-and-web-application-projects/</guid>
      <description>In Part 1, I discussed why you might want to develop your website outside of the default Ektron workarea and gave a brief overview of your options.
This time around, I’m going to show how to configure your Visual Studio Solution and projects and IIS to get you started.
You will need:
 A standard Ektron cms400min workarea website (I usually just call mine /Web – and copy directly from a fresh cms400min install!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ektron and Web Application Projects (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-03-22-working-with-ektron-using-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-03-22-working-with-ektron-using-web/</guid>
      <description>Like a lot of enterprise CMS production Ektron expects you to work in a particular way and provides lots of help for non-developers to quickly produce websites with minimal technical skills.&amp;nbsp; But what if you have more technical needs?
One of the downsides (in my opinion) of developing websites against Ektron, is the expectation that you will be integrating your code into the existing workarea Web Site Project.&amp;nbsp; Now, there are pros and cons on Web Site over Web Application projects but the big disadvantage for me is the sheer size of the workarea brings Visual Studio to a crawl when your editing code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>