<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>iis on Codifice</title>
    <link>https://codifice.uk/tags/iis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in iis on Codifice</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://codifice.uk/tags/iis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Diagnosing Tricky ASP.Net Production Issues with DebugDiag and winDbg</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-07-10-diagnosing-tricky-aspnet-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-07-10-diagnosing-tricky-aspnet-production/</guid>
      <description>Issues that (appear to) occur only in production can be very frustrating.&amp;nbsp; Recently, I’ve had difficulty with a ‘normal’ product upgrade introducing several features and fixes… the code base worked in development, passed QA and passed UAT in the staging environment.&amp;nbsp; However, 5 minutes after deploying to live the w3wp process crashes, shortly followed by the other servers in the cluster.
Bugger.
A quick look in the event logs show no unusual errors logged by the application, but the Application log records this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Example of On-The-Fly Config Section Encryption</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-05-13-basic-example-of-on-fly-config-section/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-05-13-basic-example-of-on-fly-config-section/</guid>
      <description>I recently answered a question about how you could securely modify a value within an encrypted configuration website without having to create a duplicate config file.&amp;nbsp; Well, the answer’s pretty simple and straightforward – just use the API!
A quick example page could be:
1: &amp;lt;%@@ Page Language=&#34;C#&#34; AutoEventWireup=&#34;true&#34; CodeFile=&#34;Default.aspx.cs&#34; Inherits=&#34;_Default&#34; %&amp;gt;  2:&amp;nbsp;   3: &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC &#34;-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Transitional//EN&#34; &#34;http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-transitional.dtd&#34;&amp;gt;  4: &amp;lt;html xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&#34;&amp;gt;  5: &amp;lt;head runat=&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing the Precompilation Marker File Ektron Issue on IIS 7</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-22-fixing-precompilation-marker-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-22-fixing-precompilation-marker-file/</guid>
      <description>After recently updating a 7.65 based website to 8.0 we recently found that parts of the workarea were unusable.&amp;nbsp; The upgrade went well and all the pre-deployment checks went well.&amp;nbsp; However, when we performed the UAT deployment the workarea was broken.&amp;nbsp; Where the treeview menu on the left should be, there was a helpful message:
 This is a marker file generated by the precompilation tool, and should not be deleted!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IIS 7 Gotcha! 404.13 Not Found – Uploading Large Files with Integrated Pipeline!</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-13-iis-7-gotcha-40413-not-found-uploading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-13-iis-7-gotcha-40413-not-found-uploading/</guid>
      <description>Whilst uploading a large (70MB) file to an IIS 7 website I got a 404 error….which was odd, uploading a file in a postback shouldn’t give me that.&amp;nbsp; I know that file exists!
On further investigation it turns out it was actually a 404.13 error from the Request Filtering feature of the Integrated Pipeline (more info: http://bit.ly/dkZiYr).&amp;nbsp; To fix this I needed to add some additional configuration to the &amp;lt;system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Windows 7 Development VM Load Out</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-10-my-windows-7-development-vm-load-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-04-10-my-windows-7-development-vm-load-out/</guid>
      <description>Well, it was bound to happen.&amp;nbsp; I rebuilt my PC and forgot to install my dev tools… oh well.&amp;nbsp; In an attempt to stop this from ever happening again, I’m creating a dev VM which will be backed up onto my NAS device.
The applications I’m installing for (ASP.Net Development) are:
 VMWare Player 3.0.1 (FileHippo)  2GB Memory  1 Processor  Bridged Network  40GB C: (System and Applications)  60GB D: (Data)    Windows 7 Professional x64  Firefox with Extensions:  Firebug  YSlow  Web Developer Toolbar  HTML Validator  Selenium IDE    Microsoft Web Platform Installer  Web Platform  Web Server – Recommended Products + SEO Toolkit  Framework – Recommended Products + ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ektron and Web Application Projects (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-03-24-ektron-and-web-application-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codifice.uk/posts/2010-03-24-ektron-and-web-application-projects/</guid>
      <description>In Part 1, I discussed why you might want to develop your website outside of the default Ektron workarea and gave a brief overview of your options.
This time around, I’m going to show how to configure your Visual Studio Solution and projects and IIS to get you started.
You will need:
 A standard Ektron cms400min workarea website (I usually just call mine /Web – and copy directly from a fresh cms400min install!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>